To be continued...
Maybe he meant losing Paul, but that's sadness, not regret. So...
What happens when you're traveling to Begarit?
Do you plan on leaving your family alone while you hike across the world?
Sophie...
Sophie!
Sylphie! Aisha! Norn!
Is anyone home?
They're gone. They're gone.
Oh! Big Brother!
Aisha!
You aren't hurt, are you?
No, everything's fine.
Your hand! What happened to...
Where is Norn? And Sylphie?
Oh, well... I think Norn is in class right now, but Sylphie is...
Rudy?
Rudy? Hey, what's the matter?
Sylphie, are you alright? Nothing bad happened to you?
No, I'm fine. Everyone has been wonderful to me. And Aisha's been doing such an excellent job.
And everyone else? What about Norn? Linia? Zanoba? Cliff? Are they all safe?
Safe? Of course. Nothing has happened.
Okay, so no one's sick or anything?
Um, yeah, as far as I know.
Oh, thank God.
Rudy? Big Brother?
You're okay.
Hey, welcome home.
Thank you.
Big Brother! I got Norn out of school!
You're home!
I'm so happy you're back safe.
Thanks. It's good to see you, Norn.
Okay. Now that we're all here, we need to talk.
Um, but...
Dad's not here.
He isn't.
He fought bravely, but...
Paul is dead.
This is all he left behind.
And here is ashes.
But how?
You were supposed to help him!
You should have saved him and you let him die!
Sorry, I wasn't strong enough.
But you're a mage!
You should have...
I thought you could...
Have a seat.
I'll explain everything, okay?
Okay.
So...
Do you have any questions?
You spent all that time, and couldn't save either of them.
I'm sorry.
Do you promise that you did whatever you could?
I gave it everything I had in me.
Well then, if you couldn't do it, then it doesn't even matter.
If you failed, then fine.
It doesn't matter.
Nothing could have saved our dad!
I...
Brother, do you mind if I have that sword?
Of course not.
Take it, Norn.
He'd love for you to have it.
But you can't be reckless with it, all right?
If you want to be a warrior, remember to carry a sword in your heart as well as on your hip.
And you can't protect what you love by force alone.
You need mental discipline also.
Even though you may have a blade at your side, never mistake owning a weapon for strength and courage.
I understand.
Mom?
My lady!
Will she recover?
We don't know.
But she will need looking after, so I'd like her to live here with us.
I'll leave the majority for care to Lillia.
We've already discussed that at length.
But, of course, I'm sure that we'll all need to lend a hand.
Naturally.
You can count on us.
So, um, are you saying that my mother is going to move in with us as well?
Yes.
I intend to remain in the Grey Rats' service.
Will we divide up the chores then?
Or just leave them?
We can discuss all that later.
Right.
Aisha, hey.
You don't have to hold back on our account, okay?
Mama.
Hmm.
Momma!
F unbelievablycont panicked?
Mama!
Mom, I'm so glad you're all right.
Yes, I'm okay, sweetheart.
Well, guess we better roll out and go look for an inn, huh?
You know you're welcome to stay with us tonight.
Yeah, right. Don't talk crazy, boss man.
We'd have to be real jackasses to get all up in your family time like that.
Thank you.
I appreciate everything you did for my father. It means so much to our family.
Yeah, sure thing. I'm just sorry we couldn't be more helpful.
We'll be in town for a little while, so please let us know where to find his grave once you mark it.
Of course, I will.
Come on, boss. Don't be such a gloomy Gus. Chin up!
Indeed, we've done nothing to deserve your thanks. If anyone should thank us, it's your father.
Either way, I owe you all.
Yeah, yeah. Give it a rest already. And let's go back to newbie like the olden days. What do you say?
Why are you so hung up on staying the newbie to me?
Call it superstition.
Oh, hush. Drop the tough guy act and just accept the gratitude for once.
Now, I suppose I should be off to see my sweet cliff.
You were really there for me. Thanks, Selina Lys.
Rudeus, I'm sorry about Paul.
Hey, that was my own mistake.
My duty was to avoid that entirely, to make sure that everyone came out alive.
So I accept that I failed, and I shared the blame for his debt.
I can't blame you. Or anyone.
Fine. Then you shouldn't blame yourself, either.
Right.
Sylphie? Good luck, hon.
Rudeus loves you very dearly.
I know.
Take care, yeah? Bye!
Sylphie?
Hm?
I have one more thing to say.
Huh.
Okay. Let's go in.
If it would be permissible to you, I would like to take Roxy as my second wife.
What do you mean?
After Dad died, I felt so sad and hurt.
My own life didn't seem to matter anymore.
And Roxy pulled me back from that, and suddenly I felt...
I'm sorry, Sylphie.
I said you'd be the only one, but I couldn't keep that vow.
Big brother.
Sylphie, please forgive me.
Why would she ever want to do that?
Do you have any idea how she felt the entire time she was waiting for you to come home?
She was worried sick!
Every day, it was, do you think Rudy's alright?
I miss Rudy. I wonder if Rudy is sitting down to eat right now, too.
She missed you so much and was so lonely without you, and this is how you choose to treat her?
I figured I couldn't blame you for not being able to save our dad in there.
If you lost a hand, then I can accept it was just that dangerous.
It didn't feel fair to say you weren't doing your job, but now you're telling me you had things so easy that you could spare time to take some other random woman to bed with you?
No?
No? None of this was easy.
I was hurt, and Roxy sacrificed her own feelings to save me when I hit rock bottom.
You know Selfie would have done the same thing if she had been there, so that's a stupid excuse!
Norn, you know what it's like.
Locking yourself in your room when you're so deep in despair that there's no light at the end of the tunnel?
Could you just cast aside the person who found you?
Safety.
Yeah, I know. And I'm grateful to you for helping me, but this is a totally separate thing altogether!
Lord Melis would never permit someone taking a second wife! It's wrong!
Besides, why would you want a little girl like her? She can't be any older than I am! She's tiny!
Yes, I may be little, but I am a grown woman.
Really, now? Well, that's just more embarrassing!
You should be ashamed of yourself for barging into their relationship!
Norn, that was out of line!
I'm the one who said I wanted to make Roxy part of the family, so blame me, okay?
Because she's done nothing wrong! She wanted to step aside for us!
You keep your cheating mouth shut!
If you really wanted to step aside, then why are you still hovering around our house?
You're just taking advantage of him at this point, so get out!
Yes, you're right. It was shameful.
So I'll be taking my leave.
But...
I knew there'd be resistance.
But I can't let it all end like this.
I still want to repay her.
I want her to be happy.
So what now?
What should I do?
Wait!
Roxy, please wait!
But no, why are you trying to stop her, Sylphie?
Just let her go already!
I can speak for myself.
Thank you, Norn.
Why don't you go sit down?
Now then.
I'll admit that threw me for a loop.
But it seems that thanks are in order for saving our Rudy.
Well, I don't intend to use that as an excuse.
It's true that I had ulterior motives.
I wouldn't have believed you if you said you didn't.
He is handsome, after all.
And I'd have done the same in your shoes.
You have no judgment from me.
To be honest,
I had figured it was only a matter of time
before he asked to bring another woman home.
Huh?
I mean, he's kind of a horned dog.
But he does have a big heart,
so I knew our little family would be expanding eventually.
And then,
as soon as I saw the way you looked at him,
I thought,
wow,
that's the look of a woman in love.
In any case,
I'm sorry for making things unpleasant.
It's not unpleasant at all.
Huh?
I'm not sure where I should begin.
Aha!
Ever since we were kids,
Rudy's talked about you non-stop.
How so?
Oh, just things like
Roxy is the only mage I've ever looked up to.
I'm honored,
but I'm sorry you had to hear that.
Yeah,
I did harbor some jealousy of you for a while there.
I figured you must be some incredible being.
But now that we've met,
it's clear you're just an ordinary girl
who's in love with Rudy.
Exactly like I am.
And the jealousy's all gone.
Noorn made her feelings clear,
but I welcome you.
I mean it.
So stay if you want.
Thank you for having me.
Noorn, calm down.
You can't swing so wildly during training.
It's your fault if I am,
you jerk!
Don't be mean.
Rudy's not a follower of Meely's.
Cut him some slack.
But...
Your dear father had two wives too, remember?
I guess that's true,
but it's different.
Different how?
You wouldn't treat Lelia like this.
Oh, sorry, Aisha.
Don't worry about it.
I know most of the time
you're not in the habit of thinking
before you speak.
What's that supposed to mean?
Run!
She's got a phone!
Get back here!
I was trying to approach her!
I'm really proud.
I never thought she'd take an interest
in sword fighting.
Yeah, but it makes sense
when you think about it.
When people you love and care for
go off to fight,
it can be hard to just sit on your hands
and wait around.
Sylphie.
May I ask when the baby is due?
A little over a month from now.
But if you would like to get married sooner,
don't feel like you have to wait
for the baby to get here first.
Thanks.
But to be honest,
I feel guilty taking any focus away from you.
So I don't mind waiting at all.
I can become a formal wife whenever.
Alright.
If that's what you'd prefer,
then sure.
One month.
I can't wait to meet you.
Right?
See you soon, little one.
Wow, it's really here.
Well done, Sylphie.
Sylphie.
It's a girl.
Congratulations, Lady Sylphiet.
Thank goodness.
Her hair's not green.
You should hold her, Rudy.
Huh?
Oh.
Yeah.
Here.
Like this.
She looks like you.
She does?
She does.
She's mine.
My little girl.
I love you.
Paul?
Dad.
How are you?
So, Sylphie had our baby yesterday.
A sweet girl.
And I know I'm biased, but she's already gorgeous.
I really wish you were here to meet her.
It's kind of weird to think about, but because you died,
I was here to hold my daughter.
However, if you hadn't been there to save me that day...
If it hadn't been for you, I wouldn't...
We've decided to name her Lucy.
Lucy Grayrat.
It's the closest thing to putting our names together.
And check this out, I married Master Roxy as well, so I have two wives now.
Just like you did.
I wish I had gotten more of a chance to ask you how to handle this.
Did you ever consider marrying Ghislaine or Elina Lise or anyone?
I wouldn't be surprised, but you were more open-minded than I am.
You probably didn't think that far ahead.
Maybe I should try not to overthink things either, huh?
Listen, I was a terrible son.
I have all these memories of another life, another world, so I couldn't accept you as my father.
I'm sorry for that.
I'm Paul Grayrat's son through and through.
It took a long time to sink in, but I finally realized I am just a kid.
A little brat using old memories to act like a grown-up.
But now that I have a child in this world, I figure that I need to grow up pretty quickly.
And that means making more mistakes, grieving over failure, changing slowly, gradually.
I don't think there's any other way to do it.
Thanks for setting a good example.
Okay, here I go.
I swear I'm going to make you proud.
I'll protect the ones you left behind, Dad.
Anyway, goodbye.
I'll bring the whole family next time.
So many things have fallen into place with a great deal of pain and joy.
I've repeated mistakes and haven't always learned my lesson.
But this isn't the end.
I have a lot of life to live in this world.
And I'm going to live it to the fullest.
So I can die with no regrets.
I have a lot of life to live in this world.
You have a remarkable, big, big, affected you.
I have no clue.
We want to export companies when looking at it.
第3期 政策決定